<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tunjan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tunjan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As obvious as it may be, this page aims to describe a few superficial things about myself. I may be referred to as Alberto, I was born in Málaga, Spain, though I identify myself more as an European rather than a Spaniard. That may be a factor in my decision to move to Poland, where I have been living since September, 2022. My main interests are physics, mathematics, science, rationality, and English.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>As obvious as it may be, this page aims to describe a few superficial things about myself. I may be referred to as Alberto, I was born in Málaga, Spain, though I identify myself more as an European rather than a Spaniard. That may be a factor in my decision to move to Poland, where I have been living since September, 2022. My main interests are physics, mathematics, science, rationality, and English. These topics are wide in scope, though it feels weird to name every subtopic in which I have interest, so they will not be listed.</p>
<p>I wish I could write a section to list my awards and achievements, though, because of their non-existance, I propose to give a rough sketch of how I have spent my last few years. I started a Bachelor&rsquo;s degree in Electrical Engineering, which I dropped after a couple of years because of disinterest, despite a good performance on introductory courses. Later on I started studying physics, which offered me a more pure (as in the goal of its study) and challenging enviroment, with subjectively better colleagues. A few months later I started doing a training in data science and teaching mathematics &amp; physics to International Baccaulerate students.</p>
<p>That completes the rough sketch, I hope the reader can make more-or-less accurate inferences from it. Feel free to contact me in case you want to conversate.</p>
<h2 id="learning">Learning</h2>
<p>My knowledge is currently being expanded in the following areas:</p>
<ul>
<li>Probability Theory</li>
<li>Statistical Inference/Learning</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="facts">Facts</h2>
<ul>
<li>During pandemic I started studying Japanese (with Anki) and took the JLPT N4 exam, which I failed by 2 points out of 180.</li>
<li>I am strongly in opposition against animal abuse and follow a vegan diet.</li>
<li>Run a half-marathon in Feb, 2023</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="software">Software</h2>
<ul>
<li>OS: GNU/Linux EndeavourOS</li>
<li>Environment: KDE Plasma</li>
<li>Mail Client: Thunderbird</li>
<li>Browser: Firefox &amp; Ungoogled Chromium</li>
<li>Text Editor: Neovim &amp; VSCodium</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>As expected from my previous endeavors, I find myself reluctant to write this first post. In part, this reluctance stems from my awareness that I am not in the mindset for careful and deliberate writing. However, upon further introspection, I realize a stronger correlation to the feeling of self-judgment regarding my writing skills. In any case, my aim for these posts was not to provide the reader with exceptional value, but simply to hold myself accountable.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As expected from my previous endeavors, I find myself reluctant to write this first post. In part, this reluctance stems from my awareness that I am not in the mindset for careful and deliberate writing. However, upon further introspection, I realize a stronger correlation to the feeling of self-judgment regarding my writing skills. In any case, my aim for these posts was not to provide the reader with exceptional value, but simply to hold myself accountable.</p>
<p>I fail to remember what was I learning at the start of the week. Therefore, as a lesson, moving forward I will keep track of what I have been reading.
A significant portion of my time has been spent (or otherwise invested) in reading LessWrong posts. I have found in them inspiration and motivation to keep
improving my rationality toolkit. Sometimes it feels relieving to know that there are other fellow humans who value the same things as I do. One of the posts
particularly attracted my attention, it dealt with the topic of <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/yA8DWsHJeFZhDcQuo/the-talk-a-brief-explanation-of-sexual-dimorphism">sexual dimorphism</a> and how it fits within the evolution paradigm.</p>
<p>However, my daily shifts between subjects have been counterproductive. It feels as if the way of thinking did not get into my intuition because I have not spent enough continuous time thinking about it. As an example, I can remember that when I studied Newtonian physics and spent a great deal of time thinking during problem-solving, it got to the point where I was not
leaving my Newtonian hat at the faculty, but had it even until I reached home. And now, even after a few years I am able to put that hat again as needed. Whereas, with
probability, because I have studied it intermittently and not deeply enough, I have not developed the ability to wear the hat. I hope this analogy comes through to the reader.</p>
<p>Much of this week has also been spent learning MLOps, as I&rsquo;m pursuing a course in machine learning engineering. While not the most intellectually stimulating subject (as it focuses on using existing software rather than exploring fundamental science), it&rsquo;s a comfortable area for me due to my extensive GNU/Linux experience over the past four years.</p>
<p>Some ideas I have for next week&rsquo;s post are to upload some of the problems I have had most trouble solving or have found particularly amusing to work on.</p>
<p>Finally, I list some of the books I have been reading this week:</p>
<ul>
<li>A concise introduction to Logic</li>
<li>Designing Machine Learning Systems</li>
<li>Fundamentals Of Probability</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
